[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdab", "question": "What British actor founded the London Centre for Stammering Children?", "answer": "Michael Palin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab1be6baab681b0929219c", "question": "What year did Porsche introduce the 911?", "answer": "1963", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b32324fbf195a31e15d738f", "question": "Which novel did George Eliot publish in 1876?", "answer": "Daniel Deronda", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b25fe662d71a53650fd7", "question": "Botticelli's \"Birth of Venus\" features a goddess floating in the ocean on what?", "answer": "Seashell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c972", "question": "What colour are shelled pistachio nuts?", "answer": "Green", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338883", "question": "Who wrote Around the World in Eighty Days?", "answer": "Jules Verne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c506", "question": "What is a group of hyenas called?", "answer": "A cackle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbde", "question": "With what Canadian brewery did Coors merge with in 2005 to become one of the largest in the world?", "answer": "Molson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe0003b1cf6db9ac4808d0f", "question": "What is the tallest building in South America?", "answer": "Gran Torre Santiago, Santiago, Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2ee", "question": "What US state has been led by William McKinley and Salmon P. Chase?", "answer": "Ohio", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe69afd20565ad31a57c759", "question": "What country sent troops in the form of \"Division Azul\" to assist Germany in its fight with the Soviet Union during World War II?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea4a6dff048f679a45abc3", "question": "Mariner IV sent the first pictures of which planet back to Earth?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf4", "question": "What NFL team did Vince Lombardi coach after leaving the Green Bay Packers?", "answer": "The Washington Redskins", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4e77d06d333868d34d73e", "question": "At what time of year did the Celts believe the Sun stood still for 12 days?", "answer": "Winter solstice", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdab31d0b8cce1e6fda7042", "question": "What celebrity had their dog cloned, twice?", "answer": "Barbara Streisand", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf0e", "question": "In what sport would you perform an Adolf?", "answer": "Trampolining forward 3.5 twists", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c48e", "question": "What bodily fluid surrounds a fetus?", "answer": "Amniotic fluid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bebe", "question": "What badge number was retired by the LAPD when Jack \"Joe Friday\" Webb died in 1982?", "answer": "714", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6f1", "question": "What is the longest nerve in the human body?", "answer": "Sciatic nerve", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a4", "question": "The character Lieutenant Pinkerton appears in what work?", "answer": "Madama Butterfly", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff20e7731a458464a93c423", "question": "Where did J.K. Rowling write her first novel?", "answer": "The Elephant House Cafe in Edinburgh.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a074", "question": "What song won the grammy for \"song of the year\" in 1977?", "answer": "You Light Up My Life", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b855", "question": "What suspect in the standard game of Clue has the same name as a bird?", "answer": "Mrs. Peacock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ab", "question": "What actor plays neurosurgeon Dr. Derek Shepherd in the TV show \"Grey\u2019s Anatomy\"?", "answer": "Patrick Dempsey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d2fd2596a59cbdfbd396", "question": "What's notable about Yucat\u00e1n Peninsula lakes known as \"cenotes\"?", "answer": "They are underground", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa33", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Minnesota?", "answer": "Saint Paul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc8", "question": "What was Anne's surname in \"Anne of Green Gables\"?", "answer": "Shirley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f8ba01dd7bf43be5e847", "question": "What condiment was once sold as medicine?", "answer": "Ketchup", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5af", "question": "How many bytes are there in a kilobyte?", "answer": "1024", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4bef49076251badbeaca", "question": "Which U.S. President had his sister initially serve as First Lady?", "answer": "Grover Cleveland -- \u00a0His sister Rose Cleveland took on the duties of First Lady until he married his bride Frances in June 1886.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59cdb68d65ff7d326b622a97", "question": "The 1980s \"High Society\" was a musical remake of which 1930s play?", "answer": "The Philadelphia Story", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c10d", "question": "Wiccaphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Witches and witchcraft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffcfb3d9dc5ec6cd98a8315", "question": "Who painted the Mona Lisa?", "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc1e", "question": "What year was the Rubik's Cube invented?", "answer": "1974", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b56c", "question": "How many bends does a standard paperclip have?", "answer": "Three", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb38", "question": "What is the only book of the Bible comprised entirely of law?", "answer": "Leviticus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3780a0ada16518afdc04f", "question": "What part of a chocolate bunny should be eaten first according to a majority of Americans?", "answer": "Ears", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6017402944491cbd7c5a17bb", "question": "Who ruled Soviet Russia from 1917 to 1922?", "answer": "Vladimir Lenin -- this was the period between the Russian Revolution and the formation of the Soviet Union (U.S.S.R.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c6", "question": "What year did Edward Jenner introduce the world's first successful vaccine?", "answer": "1796", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339624", "question": "Who starred as Danny Ocean in the 1960 movie \"Ocean's Eleven\"?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3ae", "question": "What name is given to rain with a particularly low pH?", "answer": "Acid rain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e2", "question": "What year was the first book of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" series first published?", "answer": "1980", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7cc6f877e98cb97778a25", "question": "Which Italian region is the source of Marsala wine?", "answer": "Sicily", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f5659e33a95c66dc4fe75a", "question": "Which 1980's sitcom featured Tom Hanks in drag on a regular basis?", "answer": "Bosom Buddies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c131877e98cb97778975", "question": "Where is Grant\u2019s Tomb?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5be580ca5415ba52ed6f0ab9", "question": "Doha is the capital of which West Asian country?", "answer": "Qatar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef5fba6ce05a3942286e46", "question": "What famous musician was nicknamed Mr. Showmanship?", "answer": "Liberace", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c7c", "question": "What famous person was the book editor at Doubleday from 1978 to 1994?", "answer": "Jackie Kennedy (Onassis)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5922002ba4edfd43a087add7", "question": "A \"Panatela\" is a type of what?", "answer": "Cigar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59523fa2736d4be723796b5a", "question": "What distiller and entrepreneur founded the town of Walkerville, which is now a heritage neighborhood of Windsor, Ontario in Canada?", "answer": "Hiram Walker", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8ab2b01dd7bf43be5e764", "question": "What does the term \"contrived patina\" mean?", "answer": "A weathered-looking surface", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60121ae563c99d48cd169b09", "question": "An \"octothorpe\" refers to which popular social media symbol?", "answer": "Hashtag -- It is also called the \"pound sign\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c6d70775fa611bce67d3", "question": "What popular 1990s toy was banned from the U.S. National Security Agency's HQ?", "answer": "Furby -- It had a recording and repeating function. It could be a problem in a place full of confidential material.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5da856251aec824685d88d05", "question": "What continent is Morocco located in?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133944a", "question": "Who played the role of Shoeless Joe Jackson in the 1989 movie \"Field of Dreams\"?", "answer": "Ray Liotta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4b7a706d333868d34d6f9", "question": "Who was the last Emperor of the Austro-Hungarian Empire?", "answer": "Karl I (or Charles I)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6018bdeed96d05b23b28165f", "question": "Who was the first person to suggest Daylight Savings Times?", "answer": "British-born, New Zealand entomologist and astronomer George Vernon Hudson is credited with the concept of daylight savings time.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c29b", "question": "What does a meteorologist study?", "answer": "Weather, more accurately atmosphere and atmospheric changes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ac4", "question": "What early rock pioneer once told an unresponsive audience, \"I hope you all get heart attacks\"?", "answer": "Jerry Lee Lewis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399fc", "question": "What 1992 film features the characters Colonel Nathan Jessup and Lieutenant Daniel Kaffee?", "answer": "A Few Good Men", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59774586284458f1d7854436", "question": "What ancient Greek god/goddess represented Necromancy?", "answer": "Hecate", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a68d", "question": "What modern-day US state was inhabited by the Calusa Indians?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c33e", "question": "How long does it take the moon to revolve around the Earth, to the nearest day?", "answer": "27", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefc1226ce05a3942286f0f", "question": "In the film \"The Bourne Ultimatum,\" where is the \"Treadstone\" facility located?", "answer": "415 East 71st Street, NYC", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76712eec85e375820b28f", "question": "Into which body of water does the Yukon River discharge?", "answer": "Bering Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac93", "question": "What is the best-known invention of Nobel Prize founder Alfred Nobel?", "answer": "Dynamite", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f34dff048f679a45aabe", "question": "What inorganic molecule does lightning produce?", "answer": "Ozone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59071d593745b36be73039d6", "question": "What operation brought over 1,500 German scientists, engineers and technicians following the end of World War II to the US to aid in military research?", "answer": "Operation Paperclip", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb8", "question": "Besides corn, what's the other principal ingredient in succotash?", "answer": "Lima beans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b817", "question": "What do you need two of to play Double Dutch?", "answer": "Jump ropes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a0", "question": "What movie starred Johnny Depp as Willy Wonka?", "answer": "Charlie and the Chocolate Factory", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c578", "question": "What nearby galaxy is name for a mythological princess?", "answer": "Andromeda Galaxy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f66", "question": "Who was the lead singer of the Sugarcubes?", "answer": "Bjork", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c3c", "question": "Who wrote the play \"Long Day's Journey Into Night\"?", "answer": "Eugene O'Neill", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c64d877e98cb977789b6", "question": "What U.S. city is known for its hot chicken?", "answer": "Nashville", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde3", "question": "What's the shortest standard reply on a Magic 8-Ball?", "answer": "Yes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ded077ea2747c8aff16d28", "question": "Ireland's River Shannon flows into which ocean?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5f9f3eeaaf848b908361b86a", "question": "What country's flag features a trident?", "answer": "Barbados", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ff7", "question": "In the Anglo-Saxon poem, who killed Grendel?", "answer": "Beowolf", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c196", "question": "Jake the Jailbird and Officer Mallory are characters that appear on which popular board game?", "answer": "Monopoly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a27", "question": "Which great Renaissance artist designed the dome of St. Peter's Basilica in Rome?", "answer": "Michelangelo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c15a", "question": "What does Karaoke literally mean?", "answer": "Empty Orchestra", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0cb", "question": "Which Kellogg's cereal was advertised by Tusk Tusk the Elephant?", "answer": "Choco Krispis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5971e0bd89261e916c8e09af", "question": "What year was the restaurant chain \"Steak 'n Shake\" founded in?", "answer": "1934", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a25f1876682715b82711ce1", "question": "Pyrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Fire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339247", "question": "What is the stage name of Gordon Matthew Thomas Sumner?", "answer": "Sting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a199", "question": "Who plays Snow White in the film \"Snow White and The Huntsman\"?", "answer": "Kristen Stewart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008dc1ef4f3bc4a292f861a", "question": "Where did Martin Luther King, Jr. give his famous \"I have a dream\" speech?", "answer": "The Lincoln Memorial (He had previously spoken to 30,000 people in 1957. This time, 250,000 people were present.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aca5", "question": "What city was R.M.S. Titanic built in?", "answer": "Belfast", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f6e", "question": "What vehicle was driven by Fred Jones?", "answer": "The Mystery Machine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a23f", "question": "What year did Elton John release his fourth studio album \"Madman Across the Water\"?", "answer": "1971", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a96a", "question": "Gouda and Edam are cities in what country?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef5b8d6ce05a3942286e17", "question": "Frank Sinatra rewrote \"High Hopes\" for what president's campaign?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c00c", "question": "In the tech field, what does AMD stand for?", "answer": "Advanced Micro Devices", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6e", "question": "At what movie's climax does Mookie throw a garbage can through the front window of Sal's Pizzeria?", "answer": "Do the Right Thing's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac13", "question": "Which ocean surrounds the Union of the Comoros?", "answer": "Indian Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5990afb4b72eedf883a8c709", "question": "Where were the Pillars of Hercules located?", "answer": "Strait of Gibraltar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d0", "question": "Which bar is the Grasshopper cocktail is said to have originated from?", "answer": "Tujague's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338965", "question": "What year was the popular French comic first published?", "answer": "1959", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfa9", "question": "What is Ronald Reagan's middle name?", "answer": "Wilson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a13", "question": "What is the name of the dog in the musical \"Annie\"?", "answer": "Sandy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a95a", "question": "Which European country replaced the Markka with the Euro?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad19", "question": "What bird did Benjamin Franklin favor for America's national emblem?", "answer": "The turkey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d9b", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"The American President\"?", "answer": "Michael Douglas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393c2", "question": "How many US soldiers were killed in the movie \"Black Hawk Down\"?", "answer": "18", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010ca970775fa611bce67fb", "question": "What were chopsticks originally used for?", "answer": "Cooking -- Their length made them ideal for reaching deep into boiling pots of water or oil.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062a09c9d816e292245c12", "question": "Which German painter was best known for his depictions of naval warfare in World War I?", "answer": "Claus Bergen (1885-1964) developed a specialty of painting naval subjects, as well as fishing scenes and coastal views.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bacf", "question": "Which sports league awards the Larry O'Brien trophy to the team that wins the yearly Championship?", "answer": "NBA", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf8", "question": "What year was the movie \"Breakfast at Tiffany's\" released?", "answer": "1961", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69b9820565ad31a57c761", "question": "Jimmy Carter served in which military branch?", "answer": "U.S. Navy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be50", "question": "What replaced the GameCube on November 19, 2006?", "answer": "The Wii", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3fe", "question": "The surface of the dwarf planet Pluto is made largely of what type of frozen gas?", "answer": "Methane", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adb0", "question": "What modern-day conglomerate built Zero fighter planes used to bomb Pearl Harbor?", "answer": "Mitsubishi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ded1feea2747c8aff16d39", "question": "The fear of speaking is known as what?", "answer": "Laliophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a37c", "question": "What city would one find the Louvre in?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe65698ae7e414034b5aecd", "question": "When Christopher Columbus sailed to America, what was the first region he arrived in?", "answer": "The Bahamas Archipelago", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c334", "question": "What percentage of air is composed of nitrogen?", "answer": "78%", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6017372e44491cbd7c5a1785", "question": "During the American Civil War, what ship engaged the iron-clad ship USS Monitor off Hampton Roads, Virginia?", "answer": "On March 9, 1862, the USS Monitor engaged the CSS Virginia in a naval battle that resulted in a draw.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399d5", "question": "The Beatles\u2019 third US album was the soundtrack to which one of their movies?", "answer": "A Hard Day's Night", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6aa3420565ad31a57c812", "question": "Who was President Gerald Ford's vice president?", "answer": "Nelson Rockefeller", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a916", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort McHenry?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a7a", "question": "What is the literary term for a word that is spelled the same backwards as it is forwards?", "answer": "Palindrome", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec85e4ec223966ae8f880b", "question": "What is the name of the first videogame in the \"Warcraft\" series?", "answer": "\"Orcs & Humans\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339128", "question": "Who composed the 1877 opera \"Samson and Delilah\"?", "answer": "Camille Saint-Saens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c6", "question": "What did Little Jack Horner pull out of his Christmas pie?", "answer": "A plum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133becd", "question": "How many Witches are in a coven?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e80464de59ea584496fea4", "question": "What are the names of the two adult Dalmatians in the novel \"The Hundred and One Dalmatians\"?", "answer": "Pongo and Missis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee2", "question": "Aron and Caleb Trask are twins in what novel?", "answer": "East of Eden", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59524338736d4be723796b67", "question": "How many of the same item can you get in the term \"Bakers Dozen\"?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f6eb9a9e54d890926f6c9", "question": "From what did the Caribbean derive its name?", "answer": "Indigenous people - The word \"Carib\" refers to one of the Amerindian groups on the islands when they were discovered by Europeans.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe76f4ceec85e375820b2e6", "question": "What is the northernmost place in the contiguous United States?", "answer": "Northwest Angle, Minnesota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b23", "question": "What book was Mark David Chapman carrying when he shot John Lennon?", "answer": "The Catcher in the Rye", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b1", "question": "Which heroine comes from Amphipolis?", "answer": "Xena", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7be", "question": "What are the four southernmost states that border Nebraska?", "answer": "Missouri, Iowa, Kansas and Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b5", "question": "Which of Henry VIII's wives may never have slept with him?", "answer": "Anne of Cleves", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b372f61c3f17ccc40c8e29", "question": "Who was the Phillips screw design named after?", "answer": "Henry F. Phillips", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6018bd93d96d05b23b28165d", "question": "What were the earliest forms of contraceptive made from?", "answer": "Crocodile dung", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee6", "question": "Who preceded Georges Pompidou as French President?", "answer": "Charles de Gaulle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600b88bb1d8c1817608d53f6", "question": "What is New York City's largest store?", "answer": "Macy's -- The flagship Macy\u2019s in Manhattan\u2019s Herald Square covers an entire NYC block, with 2.2 million sq. ft. of retail space.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f82", "question": "What was the name of Charles Dickens last novel unfinished at the time of his death?", "answer": "The Mystery Of Edwin Drood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aff9", "question": "Who won a Nobel Peace Prize in 1906 for his work at ending the Russo-Japanese War?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec26208dc25ca9e12ef647", "question": "Which country traditionally gives London's Trafalgar Square its Christmas tree?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe000ae1cf6db9ac4808d15", "question": "Which country has the oldest airport in the world that's still in operation?", "answer": "USA", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dcc", "question": "What double-word song title was a hit single by The Beau Brummels?", "answer": "Laugh Laugh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133994c", "question": "What actress replaced Farrah Fawcett on \"Charlie\u2019s Angels\" in 1977?", "answer": "Cheryl Ladd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b6b1e662d71a5365100c", "question": "What is the name of the vampire hunter and animator in Laurell K. Hamilton's \"The Harlequin\"?", "answer": "Anita Blake", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af4c", "question": "In what year was the Sony Corporation founded?", "answer": "1946", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a7f", "question": "What animator created and provided the voices for Beavis & Butthead?", "answer": "Mike Judge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ea", "question": "\"The 10 days that shook the world\" refers to what country\u2019s revolution?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc99", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Googly\"?", "answer": "Cricket", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae07", "question": "What was the first living creature to go into orbit?", "answer": "A dog", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339845", "question": "Julie Andrews won an Oscar for her role in what Disney classic?", "answer": "Mary Poppins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eadc3f83302ff91e46480", "question": "How is Alistair Leslie Graham better known as on TV?", "answer": "Ali G", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133befe", "question": "Which guitar manufacturer was responsible for the Stratocaster?", "answer": "Fender", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c72bfbde8045e48466bf", "question": "What does a cyanometer measure?", "answer": "Blueness of the sky -- It was developed by 18th-century Swiss scientist, Horace-B\u00e9n\u00e9dict de Saussure.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab1990baab681b09292191", "question": "What year was NASCAR founded?", "answer": "1948", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e5", "question": "Who founded eBay in 1995?", "answer": "Pierre Omidyar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea388bff048f679a45ab24", "question": "What scientist proposed the theory of continental drift?", "answer": "Alfred Wegener", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecdaf5ec223966ae8f88ee", "question": "Which film earned Stanley Kubrick a Razzie nomination for Worst Director?", "answer": "\"The Shining\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6bd51fb6c85e9e634ff66", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Antimony?", "answer": "Sb", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caa9", "question": "What is Diazepam better known as?", "answer": "Valium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c339877e98cb97778992", "question": "What causes the gory-looking red tint of Antarctica\u2019s Blood Falls?", "answer": "Iron", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b013", "question": "Who was \"Time\" magazine's first \"person of the year\"?", "answer": "Charles Lindburgh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae8d", "question": "What Mexican general led the attack against the Alamo?", "answer": "General Antonio Lopez de Santa Anna", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c273", "question": "What is June's birthstone?", "answer": "Pearl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b388", "question": "Acadia was the original name of which Canadian province?", "answer": "Nova Scotia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b51", "question": "What is the better known name of musician born Reginald Kenneth Dwight?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab1b4abaab681b09292199", "question": "Which company\u2019s products did the \"Wienermobile\" advertise?", "answer": "Oscar Mayer's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c56a", "question": "What chemical substance is the opposite of a base?", "answer": "Acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4a98fa61d1b4d384d5d694", "question": "What year did the radio show \"Gunsmoke\" debut as a TV show?", "answer": "1955", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8d6aa2b42d4a3561a9f06", "question": "West Swan is a suburb in which Australian city?", "answer": "Perth", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b605", "question": "Which impressionist featured his wife Camille, in \"The Woman in the Green Dress\"?", "answer": "Claude Monet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b885e662d71a53651025", "question": "Which German painter was sometimes court painter to King Henry VIII of England after 1536?", "answer": "Hans Holbein the Younger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c95e", "question": "\"Panther Cap\", \"Stinkhorn\" and \"Penny Bun\" are all types of what?", "answer": "Fungi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59cdaffe65ff7d326b622a5e", "question": "What country's entire population was condemned to death by the Spanish Inquisition?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a51", "question": "What was the complete name of the toga party band from the movie \"Animal House\"?", "answer": "Otis Day & the Knights", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa38e9c73aa70ea0b70ad6", "question": "How many U.S. states are named after a President?", "answer": "One (Washington is named after George Washington, the first U.S. president.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59029d91cad1ec93f27df74f", "question": "What company\u2019s tea shipment was destroyed during the Boston Tea Party in 1773?", "answer": "East India Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133982a", "question": "What type of music did Benny Goodman play?", "answer": "Jazz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c497", "question": "Which French philosopher said \"Cogito Ergo Sum\"?", "answer": "Rene Descartes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5eb73cea5e259d7869087332", "question": "A \"waltz-length\" dress stops at what part of the body?", "answer": "The calf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bad", "question": "How many nights are there in \"Arabian Nights\"?", "answer": "1001", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339494", "question": "In which US state does the movie \"Night of the Living Dead\" take place?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d4", "question": "Which US state has the most shoreline along the Pacific Ocean?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd94", "question": "In 2002, Sony ended production of its recorders using what doomed video standard?", "answer": "Betamax", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c43b", "question": "What is the name for the soft white layer that forms on teeth?", "answer": "Plaque", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa9456ce05a3942286ede", "question": "Where was Babe Ruth born?", "answer": "Baltimore", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f6f45a9e54d890926f6d0", "question": "Where is the \"click\"-based Xhosa language spoken?", "answer": "South Africa -- Xhosa is one of at least 35 indigenous languages spoken there.  It is a member of the Bantu family of languages.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a462", "question": "What nation is divided in two by the Cook Strait?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3bd", "question": "Why is \u00c5land known as the Islands of Peace?", "answer": "No military has entered it since Finnish takeover", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7af", "question": "On a standard QWERTY keyboard, which vowel does not appear in the top row of letters?", "answer": "A", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d9c", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Dr. Strangelove\"?", "answer": "Peter Sellers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b955", "question": "What nickname was given to mafia boss Charlie Luciano?", "answer": "\"Lucky\" Luciano", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f754da9e54d890926f709", "question": "Minnesota, it is illegal to be what in bed?", "answer": "Naked", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8d47f2b42d4a3561a9efa", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", who did Katchoo visit when she disappeared in Canada for 2 months?", "answer": "Emma", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4ce", "question": "What is a group of mosquito eggs called?", "answer": "Pallia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390df", "question": "In which play does Dame Pliant appear?", "answer": "The Alchemist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c9e7877e98cb977789fe", "question": "In Oaxaca, Mexico, Christmas Eve is also called \"Night of\" what vegetable?", "answer": "Radish", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff142ccb0ee8c595b6d39ae", "question": "What is the name of the poem John Keats wrote to a singing bird?", "answer": "\"Ode to a Nightingale\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7e3", "question": "The Benelux is a union in Western Europe that is comprised of what three neighboring countries?", "answer": "Belgium, The Netherlands, and Luxembourg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ae", "question": "Which classic TV show had a theme tune entitled \"Quiz Wizard\"?", "answer": "Blockbusters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c44a", "question": "How many chromosomes does a donkey have?", "answer": "62", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133969d", "question": "Ben Kingsley won an Oscar in 1982 for which movie directed by Richard Attenborough?", "answer": "Gandhi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c0e49076251badbeacc", "question": "Who got married in the very first White House wedding?", "answer": "Dolley Madison\u2019s sister -- Lucy Payne Washington, the sister of First Lady Dolley Madison, married Thomas Todd in 1819.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bb356622627b8fe95581bde", "question": "What year was the Jeddah Flagpole constructed in Saudi Arabia, becoming the tallest flagpole in the world?", "answer": "2014", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4b70b06d333868d34d6f7", "question": "Refugees on which ship were refused entry to both Cuba and the U.S. in 1939?", "answer": "St. Louis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bb357012627b8fe95581be1", "question": "What are the two official languages of Guam?", "answer": "Chamorro and English", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b08d01dd7bf43be5e78e", "question": "What company created the first mass-produced portable computer?", "answer": "Osborne Computers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c4", "question": "Who wrote the 1897 horror novel \"Dracula\"?", "answer": "Bram Stoker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff145cab0ee8c595b6d39bb", "question": "Richard Bachman is a pen name used by which American author?", "answer": "Steven King", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bb8", "question": "What was the colorful nickname of elderly frat member Joseph Pulasky in the 2003 film \"Old School\"?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c284", "question": "How would you write 99 in Roman numerals?", "answer": "XCIX", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a22", "question": "What Beatrix Potter character was rescued by a collie and two foxhounds?", "answer": "Jemima Puddleduck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b50f", "question": "What was the nickname of Alcatraz Prison?", "answer": "The Rock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596dfa21cf3977a46e7ce443", "question": "The abnormal fear of spiders is called what?", "answer": "Arachnophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a509", "question": "Which country was formerly known as East Pakistan?", "answer": "Bangladesh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a377", "question": "What is the capital of Norway?", "answer": "Oslo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe93b956bd93ce3a4e5f6a5", "question": "Who was the first to accurately describe the human circulatory system?", "answer": "William Harvey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394d9", "question": "What is D.J.'s full name on the TV show \"Roseanne\"?", "answer": "David Jacob", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c1", "question": "When was Indira Gandhi assassinated?", "answer": "October 31, 1984", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8adee01dd7bf43be5e780", "question": "What is the only king in a traditional deck of cards without a moustache?", "answer": "King of hearts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3bf", "question": "What does a coleopterist study?", "answer": "Beetles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a1e1e78b5a031299b745740", "question": "What year did Great Britain claim the eastern half of Australia?", "answer": "1770", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a17d", "question": "What was John Lennon's real middle name?", "answer": "Winston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b970", "question": "Which French beer is also Melton Mowbray area code without the initial 0?", "answer": "1664", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e008fe83fe1f2a824b85", "question": "What did Evangelista Torricelli invent?", "answer": "Mercury barometer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa92", "question": "Nashville is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ae94f4574a5ce6b56b824d", "question": "Which African country is Lilongwe the capital of?", "answer": "Malawi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe733f0eec85e375820b229", "question": "What naval battle between Mark Antony and Octavian is often said to mark the beginning of the Roman Empire?", "answer": "Battle of Actium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a886", "question": "The word \"serendipity\" comes from Serendip, the Persian name for what island?", "answer": "Sri Lanka", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e910598d7247dfc0fa00313", "question": "What year was the element Berkelium discovered?", "answer": "1949", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2eb", "question": "What US state has been led by Hannibal Hamlin and Edmund Muskie?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe3e92f38e4e5d4832e630f", "question": "What was the infamous Bloody Mary's occupation?", "answer": "Queen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6b8", "question": "What holds the bit in a drill?", "answer": "Chuck", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b58b01dd7bf43be5e7d1", "question": "What was Big Ben renamed to in 2012?", "answer": "Elizabeth Tower", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e96087ccba3ffe45786e7", "question": "In Greek mythology, into what did Athena turn Arachne?", "answer": "Spider", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4e9", "question": "In which country would you find the world's oldest golf course?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f0", "question": "Which continent is the home of the tsetse fly?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4b64a06d333868d34d6f0", "question": "Who first flew an airplane nonstop across the Atlantic?", "answer": "John Alcock and Arthur Brown", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ac", "question": "Which city was the first to own a subway system?", "answer": "London", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b783", "question": "Cyanide is often said to have the bitter aroma of what?", "answer": "Almonds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac8a", "question": "What city was the first American college located in?", "answer": "Cambridge, MA", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe5250d1bf59ab7d2e380f1", "question": "Where did the word \"hamburger\" first appear in the US?", "answer": "In a Walla Walla newspaper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a75b", "question": "If you take a road trip to Hawaii, what road signs would you see?", "answer": "You can't drive to Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac5c", "question": "What year did the Chernobyl disaster occur?", "answer": "1986", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f164ce1f9b80650dbe7f930", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Robinson Crusoe\"?", "answer": "Daniel Defoe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a75a", "question": "Cape Cod juts into what body of water?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a447", "question": "Which river runs through Paris?", "answer": "Seine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395cd", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is Reverend Lovejoy's first name?", "answer": "Timothy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a317", "question": "Who recorded the 1960's song \"Mellow Yellow\"?", "answer": "Donovan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133918e", "question": "Who is smarter than the average bear?", "answer": "Yogi Bear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133976d", "question": "How does Tony Montana pronounce his home country in Scarface?", "answer": "Coo-ba", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8e4", "question": "St. Louis' Gateway Arch is officially named for what US president?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339844", "question": "What three actresses were the original Charlie's Angels?", "answer": "Farrah Fawcett, Kate Jackson and Jaclyn Smith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c23e", "question": "What is the more common name for an Apiarist?", "answer": "Beekeeper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d06d10870e6f05ba600856", "question": "What 16th century physician is often credited for revolutionized anatomy by performing dissections?", "answer": "Andreas Vesalius", "category": "science"}]